export const week7Items = [
  {
    id: 0,
    answer: "1980s",
    question:
      "Computer ethics had its beginnings in the early _____, and was defined by James Moor in a paper published in 1985",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    answer: "United Nations’ World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO)",
    question:
      "According to the ____________, intellectual property is defined as: ‘the rights to, among other things, the results of intellectual activity in the industrial, scientific, literary or artistic fields’.",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    answer: "Intellectual property",
    question:
      "takes the form of intellectual objects’, such as original musical compositions, poems, novels, inventions, and product formulas.",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    answer: "Intellectual objects",
    question:
      "are non-exclusive because many people can use them simultaneously and their use by some does not preclude their use by others.",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    answer: "encryption",
    question: "Many of these technologies attempt to use ______",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    answer: "Copyright",
    question:
      "______ literally means the right to make and distribute copies to perform or display the work in public, and to product e derivative works, such as translations into other languages.",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    answer: "The Copyright Licensing Agency (CLA)",
    question:
      "The CLA was established in 1982 to protect the rights of copyright holders",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    answer: "Federation against Software Theft (FAST)",
    question:
      "FAST was the world’s first anti-piracy organization, working to protect the intellectual property of software publishers. It was formed in 1984.",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    answer: "Trademarks and Trademark Protection",
    question:
      "Another type of legal protection for intellectual property objects are trademarks.",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    answer: "Trademarks",
    question:
      "These are words, phrases, or symbols, which uniquely identify a product or a service.",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    answer: "Infringement",
    question:
      "occurs when someone else uses the trademark in connection with the sale of its goods or services",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    answer: "Dilution",
    question:
      "is applicable only to famous trademarks that are distinctive, of long duration, and usually known to the public through extensive advertising and publicity. Dilution is the result of either blurring or tarnishment.",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    answer: "Blurring",
    question:
      "occurs when the trademark is associated with dissimilar products; we can encounter descriptions such as a ‘Rolls Royce product’, meaning ‘high quality’",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    answer: "Tarnishment",
    question:
      "occurs when the mark is portrayed in a negative or compromising way",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    answer: "Software piracy",
    question:
      "refers to the large-scale and organized copying and distribution of counterfeit software.",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    answer: "Digital Rights",
    question:
      "Are the rights of individuals as it pertains to computer access and the ability to use, create and publish digital media.",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    answer: "Patent Protection",
    question:
      "definition refers to the legal exclusive rights given to an inventor for disclosing a new process, object, or invention that is useful, non-obvious, and not occurring naturally.",
  },
];

export const week8Items = [
  {
    id: 0,
    answer: "Violation",
    question:
      "________ of copyrights, patents, trade secrets and the terms of license agreements is prohibited by law in most circumstances.",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    answer: "Unauthorized",
    question: "_________ duplication of materials must not be condoned.",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    answer: "General Moral Imperative 1.5",
    question: "Honor property rights including copyrights and patent",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    answer: "General Moral Imperative 1.6",
    question: "Give proper credit for intellectual property",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    answer: "John Locke",
    question:
      "who argued that people have a natural right to the things they have removed from nature through their own labor.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    answer: "Hegel",
    question:
      "argued that property enables an individual to put their will into something.",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    answer: "Hegel",
    question:
      "property was an expression of an individual’s personality in the world.",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    answer: "David Hume",
    question:
      "who argued that a person’s creations should be owned by them to encourage ‘useful habits and accomplishments’.",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    answer: "James DeLong",
    question:
      "puts forward another point of view, defending ownership rights in terms of value.",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    answer: "Free Software",
    question:
      "is a concept and ethic that is advocated by a loose-knit, but large group of computer programmers who let people copy and modify their software",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    answer: "Richard Stallman",
    question: "president and founder of the Free Software Foundation.",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    answer: "Richard Stallman",
    question:
      "has argued, with great insistence, that all software should be free. ",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    answer: "Netscape",
    question:
      "surprised the software industry when it released the source code for its Navigator web browser.",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    answer: "Copyright Infringement",
    question:
      "is the use or production of copyright-protected material without the permission of the copyright holder.",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    answer: "Open Source",
    question:
      "commonly refers to software that uses an open development process and is licensed to include the source code.",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    answer: "Fair Use",
    question:
      "permits a party to use a copyrighted work without the copyright owner's permission for purposes such as criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching, scholarship, or research.",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    answer: "Fair Use",
    question:
      "of copyrighted material allow for the reproduction and use of copyrighted works, under certain conditions.",
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    answer: "Linux",
    question: "Which of the following is an example of open-source software?",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    answer: "open source",
    question: "Software distributed or made public in source code is called",
  },
];

export const week9Items = [
  {
    id: 0,
    answer: "Internet",
    question:
      "is arguably the most effective publishing and broadcasting medium that has ever been available to the general population.",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    answer: "Free Speech",
    question:
      "is generally understood to mean all forms of expression across all media (not just the spoken word) and in all fields of knowledge – scientific, religious and artistic.",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    answer: "John Stuart Mill (1806–1873)",
    question:
      "advocated the importance of free speech and thought.  He insisted that engagement in discussion encouraged people to think for themselves rather than simply accept ideas promoted by others",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    answer: "intellectual consequences",
    question:
      "The denial of free speech, and the free exchange of ideas, can also have __________",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    answer: "Nicolas Copernicus (1473–1543)",
    question:
      "Polish astronomer __________________ challenged the established church’s view that the Earth was at the center of the universe. He suggested that observational evidence showed that the Earth orbited the sun.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    answer: "Charles Darwin (1809–1882)",
    question:
      "proposed that all present species were derived from earlier species by the process of natural selection.",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    answer: "Salman Rushdie (1947–)",
    question:
      "British writer _____________ was born in India of a Muslim family. The Satanic Verses",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    answer: "Masrtin Scorsese",
    question:
      "US film director, screenwriter, and producer, often deals with the notion of sin and redemption.",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    answer: "Indecent speech",
    question: "is considered speech that is harmful to minors.",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    answer: "Censorship",
    question:
      "is defined as the suppression or regulation of speech (in its broadest definition) that is considered immoral, heretical, subversive, libelous, damaging to state security, or otherwise offensive.",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    answer: "Legal Sanction",
    question:
      "Freedom of speech is a principle that supports the freedom of an individual or a community to articulate their opinions and ideas without fear of retaliation, censorship, Or ___________",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    answer: "Internet",
    question:
      "it is a computer technology that allows the user to browse, share, receive, and send information to the World Wide Web.",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    answer: "Many-to-many communications",
    question:
      "Whereas it is relatively easy for a government to shut down a newspaper or a radio station, it is very difficult for a government to prevent an idea from being published on the Internet, where millions of people have the ability to post web pages",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    answer: "Dynamic",
    question:
      "Millions of new computers are being connected to the Internet each year",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    answer: "Scale and size of the Internet",
    question:
      "the Internet is huge. There is no way for a team of human censors to keep track of everything that is posted on the Web. While automated tools are available, they are fallible. Hence any attempt to control access to material stored on the Internet cannot be 100% effective",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    answer: "Global",
    question:
      "National governments have limited authority to restrict activities happening outside their borders",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    answer: "Users – adults and children",
    question:
      "it is hard to distinguish between children and adults on the Internet, and it is difficult for ‘adult’ websites to verify the age of someone attempting to enter their site.",
  },
];

export const week10Items = [
  {
    id: 0,
    answer: "Electronic mail",
    question:
      "is extremely hard to censor, especially simple, point-to-point mail, because of the distributed and robust nature of routing protocols.",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    answer: "confidentiality and privacy",
    question:
      "Cryptography has protected free expression by allowing people to express their opinions with some degree of __________",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    answer: "Cancelbot",
    question:
      "is a robot program that sends a message to one or more Usenet newsgroups to cancel, or remove from posting, a certain type of message.",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    answer: "Cancelbot",
    question:
      "It searches for messages matching a certain pattern, whether it is a duplicate message or offensive material, and sends out cancels for them.",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    answer: "Clipper chip",
    question:
      "a technology that would have been installed in all electronic communications devices, and which would have required encryption users to submit their encryption keys to a government database.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    answer: "Web Filter",
    question:
      "is a piece of software that prevents certain web pages from being displayed by a browser.",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    answer: "Filtering software or Web Filter",
    question:
      "is also used in libraries, educational institutions and other areas of public Internet use, especially those to which children have access.",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    answer: "ISPs (Internet service provider)",
    question:
      "can also implement their own restrictions on the content of websites, newsgroups and emails that are hosted on their servers.",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    answer: "Chained re-mailing",
    question:
      "By encrypting a message and then routing that message through a series of anonymous re-mailers, a user can assume that their message will remain anonymous and confidential.",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    answer: "Direct state intervention",
    question:
      "the state could amend or extend its current laws so that they apply to pertinent activities in cyberspace",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    answer: "Self-governance",
    question:
      "the Internet would develop its own semi-official political structure; it would be governed by charters established by non-profit organizations that represent the Internet’s stakeholders",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    answer: "Coordinated international intervention",
    question:
      "a new intergovernmental organization composed of representatives from countries that use the Internet could establish new rules and regulations for cyberspace that will have international jurisdiction",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    answer: "Encryption",
    question:
      "is a process that converts the original representation of the information, known as plaintext, into an alternative form known as cipher text.",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    answer: "Information",
    question: "Encryption is the process of encoding __________",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    answer: "All of these",
    question:
      "It is an internet technology tool for internet content censorship.",
  },
];

export const week11Items = [
  {
    id: 0,
    answer: "Personal information",
    question:
      "includes any information relating to, or traceable to, an individual person.",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    answer: "Personal information",
    question:
      "includes information which identifies us (our name, address and age) and information which says something about us and our lifestyles",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    answer: "Public information",
    question:
      "is information that someone has provided to an organization that has the right to share it with other organizations.",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    answer: "Data matching",
    question:
      "involves combining and comparing information from different databases.",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    answer: "Cookies",
    question:
      "are text files that websites store on the hard drive of the user’s computer.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    answer: "Cookies",
    question: "can be used for ‘data mining’ purposes",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    answer: "Spam",
    question:
      "is unsolicited bulk e-mail consisting of marketing and advertising e-mails,",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    answer: "Spam",
    question:
      "consumes a large percentage of the Internet’s bandwidth and huge amounts of storage space on mail servers and individual computers",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    answer: "Encryption",
    question: "is thus one way to ensure privacy in communication.",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    answer: "Encryption",
    question:
      "It is defined as the conversion of something to code or symbols so that its contents cannot be understood if intercepted.",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    answer: "PGP (Pretty Good Privacy)",
    question:
      "is the most widely used privacy-ensuring program by individuals and is also used by many corporations.",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    answer: "Strong encryption",
    question:
      "refers to ciphers that are essentially unbreakable without the correct decryption keys",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    answer: "RFID (radio frequency identification)",
    question: "is a wireless transmitter technology.",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    answer: "RFID",
    question:
      "tags are tiny microchips attached to an antenna that receive and transmit location information by means of radio waves.",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    answer: "Database",
    question:
      "is an organized collection of data stored and accessed electronically from a computer system.",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    answer: "Computerized Data",
    question: "is easier to collect, collate, manipulate, and analyze.",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    answer: "intellectual consequences",
    question:
      "The denial of free speech, and the free exchange of ideas, can also have _____________",
  },
];
